

Hello. My name is Albert Collell www.albertcollell.com

Software Developer



























Upcoming skills















Spoken languages

Contact:



albert.collell@gmail.com



+34 653 305 801



linkedin.com/in/albertcollell



+34 653 305 801



@albertcollell



albert.collell.5



@albertcollell

Summary:

I'm passionate about learning the latest and greatest technologies whether thats the frontend or backend. I enjoy creating sleek and responsive applications in addition to being user friendly. I love working in fast paced environments. With a highly diverse educational background and cultural experiences I excel at collaborating with teams of different knowledge sets.

A versatile engineer with interests in Software Engineering and Machine Automation. Adaptable and self motivated learner. Interested in new programming technologies, and continuous self improvement, with knowledge of Business and financial modelling in Start-up environments. Able to lead, manage and recruite people and with remote work experience.

Design Thinking

Problem Solving / Logical thinking

Leadership

Lean Methodology Agile Comunication skills

Work Experience

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

2019 - present, Remote

The One Year Nomad - Travel Blog. www.oneyearnomad.com OM3 Search - Talent Recruiting Firm. www.om3search.com

Front end development / Social media strategy / Set-up business analysis tools: google analytics, facebook pixel. / Photography

Co-founder - MOOV RIDES

2018 - 2019. Remote

The new urban movement of shared ecomobility. The most efficient and affordable electric transportation with a disruptive business model.

Strategy and vision. / Recruited a talented team. / Negotiated and created key partnerships with providers and manufacturers. / Financial modelling, forecasting and building business model / Operations strategy and plan. / Investors Pitch Deck. / Lead the funding efforts.

Co-founder - AC-BOARDS

2017 - 2018, Remote

Changing the way people move about the world. Commute, travel, leisure Smart Electric Vehicle (SEV). Electric skateboard.

Strategy and vision. / Designed product from concept to working prototype. / Established manufacturing process with Chinese suppliers and local suppliers./ Business strategy, financial modelling and forecasting.

Aerodynamics Engineer

2012 - 2016, Dassault Systems (Exa Corp).

Responsible CFD simulations and Data Analysis. Worked with cross functional teams in three different countries (Italy, Germany and Sweden) for four years.

Setup CFD simulations. / Data Analysis from the simulations. / Problem solving

Education

Full-Stack Developer Certification

2019, FreeCodeCamp.org

Certifications: Responsibe Web Design / JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures / Front end Libraries / Data visualitzation / API and MicroServices

Mechanical Enginering Degree

2007 - 2013, Politecnico di Torino (Italy) & Politecnica de Catalunya (Spain) Double degree obtained in two of the top engineering schools in Europe. Main Interests in: Fluidynamics, Thermodynamics, Macchine Design, Programming.